so what is your way of um advising men
who just start out in this journey uh
how to vet or how to find a good uh
provider here's the bottom line if your
provider needs to be taught by you as a
Layman if you need to bring them a set
of labs and say hey look this is what I
want you to test and this is why I want
you to do it that's a red flag your job
is not to educate your provider if you
need to do that great you want to make
them a better provider help them help
other people that's that's very Noble of
you don't be a guinea pig don't let
someone who doesn't know what they're
doing play trial and error on you your
health is too important you owe it to
yourself to seek someone who's competent
um if they're not testing glutening
hormone on a man who hasn't started te
yet if they're not testing shbg every
single time they do your lab if they're
not spending a few minutes explaining to
you why they're testing certain things
what these things mean why they're
prescribing you a treatment what their
desired outcome and expectations of that
treatment are then they're not servicing
you correctly now with that said I don't
want to throw every insurance provider
under the bus but when it comes to
hormones and the way the Health Care
system in America is designed insurance
is not the way to go about trt it is not
the way to go and get proper treatment
because insurance doesn't pay anything
to your provider for treating you couple
hundred bucks a year at best is not
going to get a provider to go and
dedicate themselves to spend hours a day
on the the latest in in science of how
to treat men's hormones correctly it's
just not that's not how they make their
living so by whipping that insurance
card out of your wallet you're all
already pretty much guaranteeing
yourself that you're not going to get
the proper care so unfortunately as it
stands today proper trt is self-pay out
of pocket if you want to get a provider
that is competent I spend my life
dedicated to studying this topic IC
because I am paid to do so and if I had
to take your insurance card I would not
be paid to do so I'd go do something
else and that holds true for any
provider out there uh people do care
about you this is why they're in the
field but people still have to feed
their families and they're not going to
do it for free